100 years of Disney magic comes together.
Once Upon a Studio is a animation, family,
fantasy film directed by Trent Correy.
Created for Disney's 100th anniversary, the short features Mickey Mouse
corralling a gallery of legendary Disney characters for a group photo.
Mickey Mouse (voice), played by Chris Diamantopoulos.
Minnie Mouse (voice), played by Kaitlyn Robrock.
Donald Duck (voice), played by Tony Anselmo.
Goofy / Pluto (voice), played by Bill Farmer.
Baloo / Winnie-the-Pooh (voice), played by Jim Cummings.
Moana (voice), played by Auliʻi Cravalho.
Once Upon a Studio is a 2023 American live-action animated fantasy comedy short film produced by
Walt Disney Animation Studios in celebration of the Walt Disney Company's centennial.
In the film, Disney characters come to life from pictures and
animation frames hanging on the walls of the Roy E.
Disney Animation Building following the end of a usual work day.
Combining computer graphics and traditional animation on live-action backgrounds, the short
features characters from the majority of the studio's works made up to that point.
The film was dedicated to the memory of Burny Mattinson, the company's longest-serving
employee, who made a cameo in the short and died eight months before its release.
Once Upon a Studio premiered at the Annecy International Animation Film Festival on June 11, 2023, and had its first public screening in
the United States on ABC's The Wonderful World of Disney on October 15, along with the world television premiere of Encanto.
The film explores themes of live action and animation,
dedication, short film, cgi-live action hybrid.
The tone is lighthearted.